MARCO MARCHIONNI

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+39 349 877 23 07

marco.marchionni@gmail.com

marcomarchionni.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ marcomarchionni

via Alfonso Marchesani 56, 66054 Vasto (CH) Italy

SKILLS

Languages

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, DAX

Frontend

HTML, CSS, SCSS, jQuery, React, React Native, Angular, Bootstrap, Angular Material

Backend

Node.js, Express, Spring, Spring Boot, MongoDB, MySQL

Cloud

AWS EC2 S3, Heroku, MongoDbAtlas

Tools

Git, Maven, Parcel, VSCode, Intellij Idea

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development Program CareerFoundry (2023)

Filmmaking Intensive

New York University

Laurea cum laude: Lettere Moderne University of Bologna

Erasmus Project: Art and Literature **University of Kent, Canterbury**

PROFILE

Full-stack developer proficient in a variety of programming languages and frameworks, with the ability to swiftly learn and adapt to new technologies. Developed a unique blend of creativity, technical expertise, and disciplined thinking through key roles in the film and TV industry, as well as in stock and option trading.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Portfolio Strategist

Java, Spring Boot, MySql

- Connected Interactive Brokers web server to load trading data into the app database.
- Developed REST API with Spring Boot for data querying and manipulation.
- Adopted Test Driven Development with Mockito and JUnit 5.

Flixit

Backend: Node.js, Express, MongoDb; Frontend: React, Angular

- Setup cloud database with detailed information about Italian movies.
- Constructed a REST API with Node.js and Express to enable user registration and movie information queries.
- Developed two frontend variations (React and Angular) for user login, movie information display, and favorite list creation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Stock and Option Trader

Self-employed

2013-2023

- Pursued long and short-term investment goals using planning, analitycal and organizational skills.
- Utilized Motley Fool principles for option trading, employing advanced strategies such as bull put/calls, diagonal calls, covered calls, etc.
- Built software tools with Google App Script for insight and data analysis.

TV Producer and Scriptwriter

Mediaset, Rai, Publispei and others

2001-2012, 2019-2021

- Successfully managed large TV projects through effective team management and leadership
- Produced multiple popular shows for Mediaset, a major Italian TV Network (L'onore e il rispetto, I Cesaroni, Rivombrosa)
- · Authored award-winning scripts for films and TV series.

IT Translator

Zeitgeist, London and others

2014-2019

- Translated IT documentation and marketing material for top-tier international companies (Oracle, MongoDB, Symantec, Palo Alto Networks)
- Used technical knowledge, reliability and time management skills to gain reputation among the most demanding clients.